[Music]
foreign
so far I've reviewed the evidence on
coconut oil and coconut milk that
suggests neither is good for you but
what about coconut water
when I first learned about athletes
using coconut Waters like natural
Gatorade I did a medical literature
search for athletes and coconut and only
came up with this a study of canine
athletes turns out the feeding like drug
or bomb sniffing dogs coconut oil can
sometimes wipe out their ability to
smell at all but what about coconut
water and human athletes
studies on coconut water as an
electrolyte replacement beverage date
back decades when coconut water was
compared to other Beverages and found to
be more suitable but the other beverages
they compare the two were like Pepsi
Coke Sprite and 7UP
you don't really know until you put it
to the test it was found to help in
cases of mild dehydration due to
Childhood diarrhea despite having an
unbalanced electrolyte composition by
which they meant the sodium potassium
ratio was off coconut water has so much
potassium that people with kidney
disease can run into life-threatening
hyperkalemia too much potassium in the
blood
if you drink like two quarts of coconut
water and don't have normal kidney
function which would otherwise just
flush the excess away people may not
realize coconut water has so much
potassium so even if your doctor warns
you about staying away from high
potassium foods you know you may not
realize and run into problems even one
quart a day maybe too much for someone
whose kidneys have been compromised by
diabetes for example
cream of tartar is the same kind of
thing people don't realize it's like 20
pure potassium and so when they listen
to websites claiming it's a natural
remedy even young people with healthy
kidneys can run into problems if they
take spoonfuls of the stuff with cream
of tartar overdose deaths dating back to
the 1800s
but what about rehydration after
exercise with fresh young coconut water
yes it can help replace fluid loss from
diarrhea but what about fluid loss from
heavy exercise we didn't know until this
study 90 minutes about 90 degrees
Fahrenheit until they lost up to three
percent of their body weight and then
they had them drink coconut water versus
a sports beverage versus just plain
water
and no significant difference in
rehydration for any of them subsequent
study findings were more mixed some
showed a sports drink beat out water for
hydration but coconut water didn't or
they both beat out water but not each
other but the reason athletes care about
rehydration is that they care about
performance
but there had never been any studies on
not just measures of hydration but on
physical performance until this study
they tested water versus coconut water
versus coconut water from concentrate
versus a standard sports drink then they
stuck them on a treadmill and timed how
long they could go before they collapsed
and they discovered
no significant difference between any of
them plain water did just as good as
coconut water in fact even better since
those drinking the coconut water felt
more bloated with upset tummies
now this was all done at room
temperature about 70 degrees what about
Instead at over 90 degrees Fahrenheit
then the coconut water did seem to beat
out water but time to exhaustion isn't
the same as performance that's something
that's routinely used in laboratory
studies but doing something like a time
trial test would actually measure Speed
and Performance
but there's never been a head-to-head
water versus coconut water time trial
until now
drinking coconut water bikers make it
10K in 971 seconds and on Plain water
about five seconds faster in other words
no significant difference the first
study in the use of coconut water during
exercise and it looks like it's no more
beneficial than plain water
how's the coconut water industry gonna
spin this they're the ones that funded
the study they found no difference
between plain water coconut water and
sports drinks so did the authors
conclude you know Vita Coco is no better
than water no
they said coconut water
is just as good as Sports beverages
finding athletes and coaches will likely
find of most importance failing to note
that not only did plain water do just as
well it did better because there were
twice as much stomach upset in the
coconut water groups
but wait if all the beverages did
equally well then this isn't just a
refutation of any special properties to
coconut water but the sports drinks as
well
if they didn't know better than water or
sports drinks just a waste of money
we'll find out
next
[Music]